A Finding Aid to the LeRoy Neiman Papers, 1938-2005, in the Archives of American Art AAA.neimlero
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, 1949-2005, undated; Series 3; (Boxes 20-39, 78-81; 20.2 linear feet)
  - Projects and Commissions, 1949-2005, undated; 3.1
    - NBC Peacock Project, 1997 (Box 31)
    - Nelson Mandela Tribute, 1997 (Box 31)
    - LeRoy Neiman Museum of Art, St. Paul, 1997 (Box 31)
    - Playboy's LeRoy Neiman Selection Cigars by Don Diego, 1997 (Box 31)
      - Printed Material, Photographs and Paraphernalia (Box 31)
      - Background Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 31)
      - Magazines (Box 31)
      - Magazines (Box 32)
    - Rhythm and Smoke Cigar Industry Video and CD, 1997-1998 (Box 32)
    - Blues Ball, 1997-2003 (Box 32)
    - LeRoy Neiman Website, 1997-present (Box 32)
    - Breeders' Cup Painting, 1998 (Box 32)
    - "The Culinary Arts" Solo Exhibition, Timothy Yarger Fine Art, Beverly Hills, 1998 (Box 32)
    - Goodwill Games, 1998 (Box 32)
    - Ox-Bow, 1998 (Box 32)
    - "Animals: The Wild and the Tame" Solo Exhibition, Franklin Bowles Gallery, San Francisco, October 1998 (Box 32)
    - Hofstra University Frank Sinatra Conference and Exhibition, 1998 (Box 32)
    - UCLA LeRoy Neiman Center for the Study of American Society and Culture, 1998-present (Box 32)
      - Press and Correspondence (Box 32)
      - Magazines and Catalogs (Box 32)
    - Joe DiMaggio, 1998-1999 (Box 32)
    - David Frost Wines, 1998-2003 (Box 32)
    - Good Tidings Foundation LeRoy Neiman Art Centers, 1998-present (Box 32)
    - The Fight of the Millennium, De La Hoya, Trinidad, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Holyfield-Lewis and Ali-Frazier I, 1971, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Mark McGwire, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Mike Piazza, 1999 (Box 32)
    - The Taxicab Chronicles, 1999 (Box 32)
    - PuzzleStix Product Idea, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Givenchy, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Duval-LeRoy Champagne, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Folies Bergere Neiman Chip, 1999 (Box 32)
    - John Elway, 1999 (Box 33)
    - Jesse Ventura, 1999 (Box 33)
    - Queen Elizabeth II Cruise, 1999 (Box 33)
    - Olympic Boxing, 2000 (Box 33)
    - The Art of Gaming Through the Ages, Huntington Press, 2000 (Box 33)
    - 82nd PGA Championship at Valhalla, 2000 (Box 33)
    - De La Hoya vs. Mosely, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Circus, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Cow Parade NYC, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Heavyweight Explosion, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Shaquille O'Neal, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Wilt Chamberlain, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Shelly's New York Restaurant, 2000 (Box 33)
    - "Viva el Beisbol!" Exhibition, Yogi Berra Museum, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Gibson "Art of Guitars II,", 2000 (Box 33)
    - 125th Preakness Stakes, 2000 (Box 33)
    - "A Decade of Retrospective Works by LeRoy Neiman," Hanson Gallery, New Orleans, LA, 2000 (Box 33)
    - "LeRoy Neiman-A Thirty-Year Retrospective," Timothy Yarger Fine Art, Beverly Hills, 2000 (Box 33)
    - Doodle for Hunger, I-V, 2000-2004; (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Muhammad Ali - Athlete of the Century, 2000-2002 (Box 33)
    - National All-Star Jockey Championships, 2001 (Box 33)
    - "LeRoy Neiman: Works on Paper," National Art Museum of Sport, 2001 (Box 33)
    - "LeRoy Neiman: Master Printmaker," Franklin Bowles Galleries, San Fran, 2001 (Box 33)
    - Ringside and Training Principles by Goodman and Homansky, 2001 (Box 33)
    - Art Institute of Chicago Reunion, 2001 (Box 33)
    - Dress the Jockeys at '21' Club, New York, 2001 (Box 33)
    - "LeRoy Neiman - A Retrospective Exhibition of Works on Paper," Fairfield Gallery, 2001 (Box 33)
      - Clippings and Publicity (Box 33)
      - Correspondence (Box 33)
    - Piazza San Marco, 1990, at Smithsonian, 2001-2002 (Box 33)
    - "LeRoy Neiman: Thirty Years in San Francisco," Franklin Bowles Galleries, San Francisco, 2002 (Box 33)
    - Angelo Dundee Tribute, 2002 (Box 33)
    - Wayne Gretzky, 2002 (Box 33)
    - F.D.N.Y. Painting, 2002 (Box 34)
    - Gallagher's Steak House, The Neiman Collection, 2002 (Box 34)
    - Rex Proclamation Mardi Gras Poster Painting, 2002 (Box 34)
    - U.S. Open at Bethpage Black, 2002 (Box 34)
    - Lewis vs. Tyson, 2002 (Box 34)
    - De La Hoya vs. Vargas, 2002 (Box 34)
    - Central Park Boathouse Painting, 2002-2003 (Box 34)
    - S.T. Dupont LeRoy Neiman Golf Pen and Lighter Set, 2003 (Box 34)
    - The Rocket - Roger Clemens, 2003 (Box 34)
    - "LeRoy Neiman in Cuba" Solo Exhibition, Pratt Institute, New York, 2003 (Box 34)
    - "LeRoy Neiman on Safari" Solo Exhibition, The Wildlife Experience, Denver, CO, 2003 (Box 34)
      - Press Materials (Box 34)
      - Correspondence (Box 34)
    - "A View from the Table" Solo Exhibition, Hammer Galleries, New York, 2003 (Box 34)
    - Bernie Williams, 2003 (Box 34)
    - GOAT (Greatest of All Time, A Tribute to Muhammad Ali) Book by Taschen, 2004 (Box 34)
    - De La Hoya vs. Hopkins, 2004 (Box 34)
    - Special Olympics, Nagano, Japan, 2005 (Box 34)
    - Las Vegas Centennial, 2005 (Box 34)
    - "LeRoy Neiman: The Art of Boxing," Franklin Bowles Galleries, 2005 (Box 34)
    - Long Term Project, American Sportscasters Association Hall of Fame Awards Dinner, 1984-2005; (4 folders) (Box 34)
  - Neiman Publications, 1950-2004, undated; 3.2
    - LeRoy Neiman Art and Lifestyle, 1974, Felicie (Box 35)
      - Clippings, Publicity, Photos (Box 35)
      - Magazines and Catalogs (Box 35)
      - Text drafts of Introduction and Chronology (Box 35)
      - Text Drafts (Box 35)
      - Notes on Boxing (Box 35)
      - Notes (Sociological), (3 folders) (Box 35)
      - Notes, (2 folders) (Box 35)
      - Notes on Topics Left Out of Book (Box 35)
      - Lists of Drawings (Box 35)
      - Descriptions of Paintings (Box 35)
      - Correspondence (Box 35)
    - Moby Dick, The Artist's Limited Edition, 1975 (Box 35)
    - Horses, Harry N. Abrams, 1979 (Box 35)
      - Publicity, Reviews, and Related Exhibitions (Box 35)
      - Notes, (2 folders) (Box 35)
      - Captions (Box 36)
      - Binder Notebooks of Image Lists and Essay (Box 36)
      - Correspondence (Box 36)
      - Magazines, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Posters, Harry N. Abrams, 1980 (Box 36)
    - The Prints of LeRoy Neiman, Knoedler Publishing, 1980 (Box 36)
    - Carnaval, Knoedler Publishing, 1981 (Box 36)
    - Winners, Harry N. Abrams, 1983 (Box 36)
      - Publicity and Related Exhibitions (Box 36)
      - Magazines and Catalogs (Box 36)
      - Photos, Proofs and BLAD (Box 37)
      - Text Drafts, (3 folders) (Box 37)
      - Correspondence (Box 37)
      - Winners, Japanes Edition, 1985 (Box 37)
      - Notes on Auto Racing and Basketball (Box 37)
      - Notes on Baseball and Cricket (Box 37)
      - Notes on Boxing (Box 37)
      - Notes on Bullfighting, Cock Fighting, Coaches, Dance, Dog Racing and Football (Box 37)
      - Notes on Gambling, Golf and Hockey (Box 37)
      - Notes on Horse Racing and Miscellaneous Sports (Box 37)
      - Notes on the Olympics (Box 37)
      - Notes on Skiing, Soccer, Sumo and Martial Arts and Sports Lists (Box 37)
      - Notes on Skating, Tennis and Water Sports (Box 37)
      - Miscellaneous Notes (Bio and Sociological) (Box 37)
      - Miscellaneous Notes and Interviews (Box 38)
      - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 38)
      - Final Drafts of Captions, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Monte Carlo Chase, Van Der Marck Editions, Ltd., 1988 (Box 38)
      - Press (Box 38)
      - Magazines (Box 38)
      - Correspondence (Box 38)
      - Related Exhibitions (Box 38)
      - Manuscript of "Over the Edge,", 1986 (Box 38)
      - Manuscripts, 1987 (Box 38)
    - The Prints of LeRoy Neiman, 1980-1990, 1991 (Box 38)
    - Big Time Golf, 1992 (Box 38)
      - Manuscript and Press Kit (Box 38)
      - Correspondence, Notes and Book Tour Itineraries etc. (Box 38)
      - Publicity and Related Exhibitions (Box 38)
      - Photos (Box 38)
      - Magazines and Catalogs (Box 39)
      - Saks Fifth Avenue Catalogs (Box 39)
    - LeRoy Neiman: An American in Paris, 1994 (Box 39)
      - Press (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Related Exhibitions (not including Galerie Marcel Bernheim, Paris 1993? see 3.1: "Un Americain à Paris," Solo Exhibition, Galerie Marcel Bernheim, Paris 1993) (Box 39)
    - LeRoy Neiman On Safari, 1996 (Box 39)
      - Press (Box 39)
      - Related Exhibitions (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Zoo Tour Correspondence (Box 39)
    - Casey at the Bat, 2000 (Box 39)
      - Press and Publicity (Box 39)
      - Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - The Prints of LeRoy Neiman, 1991-2000 (Box 39)
    - LeRoy Neiman: Five Decades, 2003 (Box 39)
      - Clippings and Publicity (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Design Drafts (Box 39)
    - LeRoy Neiman Sketchbook: Liston vs. Clay 1964/ Ali vs. Liston 1965, 2004 (Box 39)
    - Publications, General (Box 39)
    - Oversized Project Files, 1950-1980 (Box 78 (sol))
    - Oversized Project Files, 1960-1980 (Box 79 (sol))
    - Oversized Project Files, 1990-2000 (Box 80 (sol))
    - Oversized Project Files, 1990-2000 (Box 81 (sol))
- Printed Material, circa 1940s-circa 2005, undated; Series 4; (Boxes 40-61, 82-83, OV 85; 21.6 linear feet)
  This series consists of printed material in which the artist's work or name appears including newspapers, magazines, catalogs, fliers, invitations, publicity brochures, press releases, film scripts, small posters, and other miscellaneous items.
  Magazines in which the artist's work appeared only sporadically can be found either in 4.1: Dated Files, or in a project file in Series 3: Project Files. Specific magazine titles can be searched for in the Index.
  Printed materials dated only by decade are placed in a file at the start of the decade to which they belong. The series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  4.1: Dated Files, circa 1940s-circa 2005
  4.2: Magazine Collections, circa 1950s-circa 2005, undated
  - Dated Files, circa 1940s-circa 2005; 4.1
    This subseries contains contains chronologically arranged printed material.
    - 1940s (Box OV 85)
    - 1950-1971, (16 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1972-1977, (15 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1978-1981, (14 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1981-1984, (13 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1985-1987, (15 folders) (Box 44)
    - 1988-1990, (17 folders) (Box 45)
    - 1990-1994, (15 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1995-1996, (11 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1996-1999, (8 folders) (Box 48)
    - 2000-2002, (10 folders) (Box 49)
    - 2003-2005, (8 folders) (Box 50)
  - Magazine Collections, circa 1950s-circa 2005, undated; 4.2
    This subseries contains collections of magazines in which the artist's work appears regularly over the course of several years. The collections are listed in alphabetical order and are arranged chronologically thereafter.
    - Bartender Magazine, 1982-2002; (3 folders) (Box 50)
    - Legends NFL Alumni Magazine, 1982-2002; (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Arts Magazine, 1975-1981; (15 folders) (Box 51)
    - The Ring, 1966-2002; (3 folders) (Box 51)
    - The Ring Digest and Almanac, 1998, 1999; (1 folder) (Box 51)
    - Playboy, 1954-1962; (19 folders) (Box 52)
    - Playboy, 1963-1966; (14 folders) (Box 53)
    - Playboy, 1966-1969; (13 folders) (Box 54)
    - Playboy, 1970-1972; (12 folders) (Box 55)
    - Playboy, 1973-1978; (13 folders) (Box 56)
    - Playboy, 1978-1981; (11 folders) (Box 57)
    - Playboy, 1981-1985; (15 folders) (Box 58)
    - Playboy, 1986-1997; (17 folders) (Box 59)
    - Playboy, 1998-2002; (8 folders) (Box 60)
    - Playboy, Non-US Editions, (1 folder) (Box 60)
    - VIP Playboy Club Magazine, 1964-1975; (4 folders) (Box 60)
    - Playboy's "LeRoy Neiman Sketchbook" Feature Tearsheets, (1 folder) (Box 60)
    - Playboy Tearsheets (Box 60)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 60)
      - 1950s, (2 folders) (Box 60)
      - July 1956 (Box 60)
      - 1960s-1970s (Box 60)
      - 1990s (Box 61)
      - 2000s (Box 61)
    - Playboy Parodies (Box 61)
    - Playboy Parodies, Harvard and Yale (Box 61)
    - Playboy, Femlin Paraphernalia (Box 61)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 61)
      - Playboy's Party Jokes Books (Box 61)
    - Playboy Ephemera, 1950s (Box 61)
    - Playboy Ephemera (Box 61)
      - Press and Paraphernalia (Box 61)
      - Magazines and Calendars (Box 61)
    - Playboy Scrapbook, 1961-1967 (Box 61)
    - Playboy Ephemera, 1970s (Box 61)
      - Press and Paraphernalia (Box 61)
      - Magazines and Calendars (Box 61)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 61)
    - Playboy Ephemera, 1980s (Box 61)
    - Playboy Ephemera, 1990s (Box 61)
    - Playboy Ephemera, 2000s (Box 61)
    - Oversize Printed Material (Box 82 (sol))
    - Oversize Printed Material (Box 83 (sol))
- Artifacts and Artwork, 1953-2002, undated; Series 5; (Boxes 69-76, 84; 4.8 linear feet)
  This series consists of three-dimensional items and non-print items such as clothing, LeRoy Neiman paraphernalia, and souvenirs.
  The items are listed as they are stored, by box. Wherever possible, items are listed chronologically within boxes, with dates proceeding directly from box to box among the small artifact boxes. Large artifacts are arranged and listed according to the unique storage requirements of each item.
  Artifacts listed here include three-dimensional items from Series 1: Biographical Materials and Series 3: Project Files. These items are listed with a heading that directs researchers to the corresponding file.
  - 3 framed ceramic tiles depicting baseball, basketball, and football scenes reproduced from LeRoy Neiman paintings (Box 69)
  - Femlin 1953-present, 3 Femlin Coasters, undated (Box 69)
  - Promotion Proofs for World Series, 1966; (3 pink embossed cards) (Box 69)
  - Metal Plaque, Art Directors Club of Oklahoma City, 1967 (Box 69)
  - Fifth Dimension Album Art, CD of "Portrait,", 1970-1982 (Box 69)
  - Dummies for Plastic Souvenir Cups, 1970s (Box 69)
    - Tall Cup with Alabama Handoff, Decoration, 1973 (Box 69)
    - Short Handled Mug with Tennis Painting (Box 69)
  - Pendants Bearing LeRoy Neiman paintings in miniature, 1970s (Box 69)
    - Secretariat at the Lead, 1975 (Box 69)
    - Hoosier Hoopla, 1976 (Box 69)
  - Newport Jazz Festival 1975-2004, (CD for 2004 Newport Jazz Festival with artwork on disc and case) (Box 69)
  - Neiman's Restaurant and Lounge paraphernalia, 1980s (Box 69)
    (menus, napkins, drink stirrers and a matchbook from this restaurant in California, which uses Mr. Neiman's name and displays his serigraphs, but was created without his knowledge or participation, as there is no copyright on his name or image)
  - Nametags and IDs (Box 69)
    - Leather Wallet (containing badge naming Neiman as an Honorary Deputy Constable of the City of Las Vegas), circa 1980s (Box 69)
    - Vinyl Card Wallet (with cards), 1980s (Box 69)
  - American Sportscasters Association Hall of Fame Awards Dinner, 1984-1997 (Box 69)
    (souvenir canister from third annual dinner, bears reproduction of LeRoy Neiman drawing on lid)
  - Chef John Bennett T-shirt with Neiman Silkscreen, 1988 (Box 69)
  - Classic Moments Watches, 1989 (Box 69)
    (tray of changeable watch faces bearing miniature reproductions of Neiman paintings)
  - Denver Grand Prix, Lucite Plaque with Reproduction of Denver Grand Prix, 1990-1991 (Box 69)
  - Playboy Electronic Datebook, 1993; (three 3 ½ inch floppy disks with user's manual and box) (Box 69)
  - "LeRoy Neiman/The Impressionist Collection" Note Cards, 1993 (Box 69)
  - Frank Sinatra Duets and Duets II Album Covers, 1993-1995; (two CDs in jewel cases with inserts) (Box 69)
  - Miniature Replica World Boxing Association Championship Belt, 1996; (engraved with LeRoy Neiman's name, 'bejeweled' leather and metal with faux sheepskin backing and Velcro closure) (Box 69)
  - The Art of Playboy CDROM, 1997; (in box, still in plastic wrapping) (Box 70)
  - Panorama, Jim Hall CD, with Neiman Cover Art, 1997 (Box 70)
  - Awards, Key to the City of Las Vegas, 1997 (Box 70)
  - 123rd Kentucky Derby and Derby Day Paddock Decorative Picture Frame, 1997 (Box 70)
  - Playboy's LeRoy Neiman Selection Cigars by Don Diego, 1997; (mock up cardboard cigar box and wooden cigar box) (Box 70)
  - Rhythm & Smoke: The Cuba Sessions, 1997-1998; (2 CD's with English and Spanish covers) (Box 70)
  - Folies Bergere LeRoy Neiman Chips, 1999; (2 chips bearing LeRoy Neiman images in a black presentation box, Duvall-LeRoy Elegance de Champagne Cuvee LeRoy Neiman; 2 one-bottle boxes; one metal cork cap) (Box 70)
  - 82nd PGA Championship at Valhalla, 2000; (service ID badge with metal clip and neck strap) (Box 70)
  - Frank Sinatra "Classic Duets" Album Cover 2002 - CD still in plastic wrapped jewel case (Box 70)
  - Hats (Box 71)
    - One paint-covered off-white newsboy cap, 1970s (Box 71)
    - One blue chef's cap with "LeRoy" signature embroidered in red on one side, heart emblem on other side (Box 71)
    - Femlin 1953-2005 - one cap with Femlin character on front and Femlin brand label and LeRoy Neiman signature embroidered on back (Box 71)
    - 1984 Olympics, Los Angeles - one 1984 Olympics painter's cap, with a message to LeRoy Neiman from the mayor written in pen on side of cap (Box 71)
    - Dodgers Centennial, 1990 - one Dodgers Centennial cap (Box 71)
    - Playboy's LeRoy Neiman Selection Cigars by Don Diego, - one Playboy Cigars by Don Diego cap, denim with suede bill, 1997 (Box 71)
  - Shoes (Box 71)
    - Three single sneakers, paint covered, two signed and dated by Neiman (Box 71)
    - One pair of leather moccasins (Box 71)
  - Large Artifacts (Box 72 (sol))
    - Tray with reproduction of painting of a Boston Red Sox player (Ted Williams?) swinging a bat; this is a template of a product which was never produced, undated (Box 72 (sol))
    - The Heavyweights vinyl LP with album art by Neiman, 1970, still in original plastic wrapper 1984 Olympics, Los Angeles - A plaque from the Japanese magazine "Shukan T.V. Guide," thanking Neiman for his help on their Olympics edition magazine cover, which shows a painting of an Olympic runner. (Box 72 (sol))
    - Sign promoting the release of The Golden Bear, 1992 serigraph of Jack Nicklaus (Box 72 (sol))
    - Celebration 2000 - Plaque given to LeRoy Neiman by Centaur Galleries on the occasion of his Celebration 2000 exhibition, naming him "Artist of the Decades" (Box 72 (sol))
    - Photographs - Framed photograph of LeRoy Neiman and Charles Barkley unveiling portrait of the basketball player on the occasion of his retirement, 2001 - back of frame has LeRoy Neiman's handwritten note describing the photo (Box 72 (sol))
    - Two empty sample boxes for jigsaw puzzles of the 1983 painting, Elephant Family, 1999 (Box 73 (sol))
  - Bags (Box 74 (sol))
    - London Playboy Club shoulder bag, 1960s (Box 74 (sol))
    - Steve Garvey Sports Classic tote bag, 1980 (Box 74 (sol))
    - Larry Bird, 1993 - Larry Bird Night duffel bag (Box 74 (sol))
  - Clothing (Box 75 (sol))
    - Yellow Nomex suit with Lynn Quayle's name embroidered on breast (Box 75 (sol))
    - White satin bomber jacket with "LeRoy" embroidered on breast and stunt person agency logo on back (Box 75 (sol))
    - Silk men's shirt printed with a collage of Neiman works in sepia tones (Box 75 (sol))
    - Femlin T-shirt, 1953-2005, 1999-2000; (3 brand label t-shirts) (Box 75 (sol))
    - Hambletonian Harness Race Painting, 1995; (t-shirt with Hambletonian name and reproduction of painting on front) (Box 75 (sol))
    - 2 T-shirts from the "Fringe TOMAR 2000" Festival Internacional de Danca Contemporanea, LeRoy Neiman image reproduced on front or back of shirt (Box 75 (sol))
  - Paint Clothes, (6 pairs pants, 2 jumpsuits, 1 shirt) (Box 76 (sol))
  - Oversized Drawings and Artwork, undated (Box 84 (sol))